本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigamiorg)制作仅供交流学习禁止用于任何商业用途
Is that...
あれは
Could that be...
日听：小伍King翻译：森罗小江校对：Syura时间轴：海底压制：Coolkid
あれはもしや
The Skytree?!
スカイツリ
No, that's just a transmission tower.
いやあれはただの鉄塔だね
Nekoma
Metropolitan
High School
Here we are, Tokyo!
来たぜトキョ
The scenery's not that different from Miyagi.
風景あんま宮城と変わんねな
Well, we're in the suburbs.
そりゃ郊外だからな
Walk faster!
キリキリ歩け
Hey, wait.
ていうかおい
Aren't you missing some people?
なんか人足んなくねか
Actually...
実は
これが先輩の
This is how awesome...
実力だぜ
...your upperclassmen are!
You both barely got over the 40 points needed to pass.
お前らだて４０点の赤点ギリギリじゃん
あれ日向は英語自信あたんじゃ
Huh? Hinata, you failed English?
But you were so confident.
Apparently, he figured out right before time was up that he'd filled in all his answers off by one.
終了間際に解答欄が１コズレてたことに気づいたみたいで
Seriously?
マジか英語の小野先生そういうの許してくれないんだよなぁ
Too bad Ms. Ono, the English teacher, won't let things like that slide.
Yachi was really shocked by it too.
谷地さんもスゲショク受けてました
合てるのに合てるのにィィィ
But they're right... But they're right!
In Kageyama's case, the issue was Modern Literature.
影山は現文か
Apparently, there were a lot of reading
comprehension questions this time around,
今回はやたら読解問題が多かたぽくて
but he'd concentrated on memorization when he studied.
暗記系に絞てたみたいだから
Wow, he got a perfect score on the kanji section. Dang.
漢字は満点だスゲ
Well, don't be too discouraged.
まああんまり落ち込むなよ遠征は今回だけじゃないん
We'll have more away games later, so—
How are we gonna get to Tokyo?
どうやて東京まで行く
Should we run?
走るか
Nah, we need bikes.
チャリだろ
行く気だ
They're totally planning on going!
おいお前ら
Hey, you two.
Huh?
So the power duo's retaking some tests right now?
じゃああの超人コンビ今頃補習受けてんの
Yeah... But, well...
ああまあでも
There...
女子が二人になとる
There're two girls now!
Now they've got a pretty one and a cute one!
キレイ系とカワイイ系
モヒカン東京凄い
Whoa, a mohawk. Tokyo's intense.
Do you see, Tora?
見たか虎よ
This is what Karasuno's true ability looks like.
これが烏野の本気なのです
Ugh! So bright!
眩しい
Let's go.
行こう
R-Right.
All right. When you're all ready, come to the gym.
じゃ準備できたらすぐ体育館来いよ
The other teams are already there.
もう他の連中も集まてきてる
Yeah.
Episode Four:
"Center Ace"
Would you look at this? You two look unusually serious.
いつになく真剣だなお前ら
You guys only failed one test, right?
お前ら赤点は１コだけだな
You should be able to finish retaking it in the morning.
それなら補習は午前中で終わるはずだ
After that, I'll call in your savior.
そしたら俺が「救世主」を呼んでやろう
頑張れよ
Do your best!
What's up, failures?
ヘイ赤点ボズ共
乗りな
Get in.
A-Are you Tanaka's older sister?
た田中さんのお姉さんですか
Call me Saeko.
冴子姉さんと呼びな
I'll get you two to Tokyo in the blink of an eye.
東京までなんてあという間に届けてやるよ
Saeko!
冴子姉さん
おし行くよ
Strap in, 'cause here we go!
Okay!
However, the safety and comfort of the ride
cannot be completely guaranteed.
ただし乗車中の安全性及び快適性等については一切保障致しません
However, the safety and comfort of the ride cannot be completely guaranteed.
Thank you for understanding.
ご了承ください
It's been a while,
お久しぶりです猫又先生
Coach Nekomata.
Glad you could come all this way.
おおよく来たな
Thanks for letting us take part in the group practices.
この度は合同練習に参加させていただき本当にありがとうございます
No, it was nothing. We'll definitely be taking a close look at your progress since last we met.
いやいやこちらこそしかり見せてもらいますよ
あれからどれほど力を付けたのか
Let's have a good match!
お願いします
Wait... Where's Shouyou?
あれ翔陽は
Seems he had to retake a test.
補習だてよ
I see.
Nice!
ナイス
All right!
There!
Good!
All right!
Okay.
Nice!
Okay!
アプとたらこの中に入て
Once we're done warming up, we'll regroup and the teams will play each other in a rotation.
あとはひたすら全チムでぐるぐるとゲムをやる
Right.
After each set, the losing team has to run one lap around the court, diving.
１セト毎に負けた方はペナルティでフライングコト一周
Diving?
フライング
They're going to act like they're diving to dig out a ball.
空中でボルを拾う「フライングレシブ」をする時の動きで
They'll slide across the floor on their chests with their arms extended.
手胸の順で体を床に滑らせるの
向こうに対戦校あるから研究して
Take a look at the match lineup over there.
Hey, was that guy with Nekoma the last time we had a practice match with them?
駒にあんな奴いたけ
You should be up against Shinzen first.
確か１戦目は森然とあたるはず
Got it.
Huh?
わかた
The guy who's staring really hard at us?
めちゃこち見てる奴
Yeah.
I'm pretty sure he wasn't.
あいやいなかたと思うけど
Hey, stop sulking already.
オラそんなに思い詰めんな焦るのはわかるけどなぁ
I know you're in a hurry, okay?
There are some flowers you only see when you take detours.
回り道には回り道にしか咲いてない花があんだからさ
I don't really get it, but that sounds awesome!
よくわかんないけどかけ
It means you should be thankful for your failing grade,
because now you get to ride with me.
アタシの隣でドライブできてんだから赤点に感謝しろてこと
Whoops.
そんな思い詰めるほどバレ好きなんだな
You must really love volleyball if you're so concerned.
Yes!
When did you start playing?
翔陽はなんでバレ始めたの
小学生の時テレビで春高を見たんです
When I was in grade school,
I saw the spring nationals on TV!
I caught it right as Karasuno was playing, and...
ちょうど烏野の試合でそれで
I saw the Little Giant!
You saw the Little Giant,
小さな巨人を見た/見たんです
am I right?
Guess I was right.
やぱ当たた
冴子姉さん小さな巨人知てるんすか
You know the Little Giant?!
I'm pretty sure I went to school with him.
アタシ多分そいつと同級生だもん
What?!
But I never spoke to him.
つてもしゃべたこともないけどさ
I probably would've known him better if he was the mischievous type and stood out.
ヤンチャな奴なら目立つだろうし
知り合いだたと思うんだけどねぇ
Were you like the sort of person who was friends with all the bad guys?
姉さんは「悪そうな奴は大体友達」てやつですか
Pretty much, yeah!
それだな
けどさぁ
But...
One time, when I saw them playing a practice match or something,
たまたま学校で練習試合やてんの見かけた時
he looked way scarier than any of the scary-looking people I knew.
そいつはどんな強面の知り合いよりも怖かたよ
Actually, it was more like he was really intense.
怖いていうか迫力が凄くて
You mean the way he'd spike the ball?
スパイクがですか
Nah.
Maybe he wasn't feeling his best at the time,
but he was being switched out.
そん時は調子が悪かたのか途中で交替させられててさ
Karasuno                                         Yugama
He's what you guys call an ace, right?
あいつは所謂「エス」て奴だたんだろ
You could see the absolute pride and confidence of being the ace rising up from his body.
自分がエスであることの絶対的プライドと自信
そういうのが全身から立ち上てんだ
I nearly fell for the guy on the spot.
危うく惚れるとこだたわ
Anyway, when the ace is in action,
でエスが活躍すれば同時に周りの連中は
everyone around him acts like they
aren't gonna let him do all the work.
エスに「おんぶに抱こ」状態になてたまるかて奮い立つ
You really know a lot about the Little Giant.
姉さん小さな巨人に詳しいんすね
Not really! I just happened to see some of his matches, that's all!
別にたまたま何回か試合見ただけだし
So you were awake, huh?
つか起きたのかよ
I got hungry.
腹が減たんで
Do you just follow your instincts?
本能の赴くままか
Yes.
We won't get weaker just because you watched us.
見られることで俺達が弱くなることはない
自分がエスであることの絶対的プライドと自信
The absolute pride and confidence of being the ace...
All right, we're almost there.
さああと少しだ
飛ばすよ
I'm flooring it!
Number seven!
Karasuno                     Fukurodani
７番
One blocker!
１枚
Nice receive, Nishinoya!
西谷ナイスレシブ
They're going left!
レフトだレフト
Damn it!
Karasuno                     Fukurodani
They're quite good.
さすがに強いですね
Yeah.
One lap of diving drills!
フライング一周
Yessir!
おす/おい
別にこちの調子が悪いわけじゃね
It's not like we're doing that badly either.
They're just the kind of team who can make it to nationals.
これが全国レベルてやつなんだろ
Give us a good serve!
ナイサ
くそタラコめぇ
Damn it, Tarako!
Their arms are gonna snap off!
腕もげる
あそこのチム全員のサブが凄いんだよね
Everyone on that team is really good at serving.
The manager from Ubugawa mentioned that.
生川のマネさんが言てましたねとにかくサブに力入れてるて
They put their all into their serves.
Yeah.
It must be pretty hard to have to do a hundred serves at the end of practice.
練習のラストに毎回１００本サブてかなりきついと思う
Give us another good one!
もう一本ナイサ
Ubugawa High School's serves are their ultimate attacks.
サブこそが究極の攻め生川高校
Ubugawa High School
(Kanagawa)
But once we're able to dig out a serve...
でも一度このサブを上げることができれば
Bring it!
来いやァ
Whoa! They're all moving at once?!
なんか一斉に動き出した
Too bad, I'm actually over here!
残念こちでした
凄い連携
That was an amazing combo.
Th-There are people jumping up all over the place.
あちこちから人が飛び出してきてもう誰が打つのやら
I can't tell who's going to hit it.
Yeah!
They're truly the masters of combination attacks.
まさにコンビネションの匠森然高校
Shinzen High School
(Saitama)
Shinzen High School.
Shinzen High School
(Saitama)
And then we have our destined rivals...
さらに因縁のライバル
Yaku!
夜久さん
Like always, they're excellent at receiving.
相変わらずいいレシブしやがる
The school that's known to dig out balls,
keep them in play, and wait to counterattack:
駒高校
Nekoma High School
(Tokyo)
Nekoma High School.
Nekoma High School
(Tokyo)
Two blockers!
ブロク２枚
And...
そして
すまんカバ
Sorry, cover me!
Okay!
Take that!
Akaashi!
赤葦
Just like Ushiwaka...
ウシワカ同様全国で５本の指に入るエス
木兎さん
Bokuto!
...he's one of the top five aces in the country.
Tsukki!
Hey, Kenma! Don't run from that!
コラ研磨逃げるな
My arms will rip off.
腕もげる
もげない
They won't rip off!
We're very thankful...
本当にありがたいです
All right!
よしゃ
I'm so awesome!
俺て最強ヘイヘイヘイ
Hey, hey, hey!
全国を戦う大エス擁する強豪チム梟谷学園
Fighting at nationals, a powerhouse with a great ace:
Fukurodani Academy
(Tokyo)
Fukurodani Academy.
It's amazing that we can face such great teams.
こんなチムと戦えるなんて
Yeah.
だが相手の強さにビビてる場合じゃね
However, this is no time to be scared of how good our opponents are.
俺達はこいつらと渡り合ていかなきゃいけねぇんだ
We have to be on the same level as these guys.
Karasuno                  Ubugawa
All right!
よしじゃあフライング一周
One lap of diving drills!
おす/おい
Yessir!
How many losses are they up to now?
あいつら何敗目だよ
They're not exactly weak, just sorta... mediocre.
別に弱くないけど平凡だよな
Who are the first-years that Nekoma had such a hard time with?
音駒が苦戦したヤバイ１年てどれのことだよ
Maybe the guys from Nekoma
overestimated them or something?
音駒の連中の買いかぶりすぎじゃ
Hitoka, hold it back. There, there.
仁花ちゃん抑えてどうどう
It's okay.
大丈夫田中の言うことが本当ならもうすぐ
If what Tanaka said was true,
they should be here any second now.
Hey, they're still at it.
まだやてんじゃん
間に合たね上出来
We totally made it. Not bad at all.
Big Sis!
姉さん
Wait, that's your sister?
え西谷のお姉さん
No, she's Ryuu's sister.
いえ龍のです
You're right. I can see the resemblance.
確かに似てる
Glad they made it in one piece.
無事でよかたぜ
主役は遅れて登場てか腹立つわ
So the stars are showing up fashionably late?
How annoying.
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
Nice serve!
ナイサ
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
Hey, what was that?
おい何だよ
So fast...
すげぇ速い
I've never seen a fast attack like that.
あんな速攻見たことねぇ
次止めるぞ
We're stopping the next one!
Yessir!
ナイサ
Give us a good serve!
すまんカバ
Sorry! Cover it!
Eikichi, I'm counting on you!
栄吉頼む
Wow, nice serve! Not bad!
いいサブやるな
Nice, Hinata!
日向ナイス
Eikichi! Stop their number ten!
栄吉１０番止めろ
Shinzen                 Karasuno
Damn it!
クソちょと掠たけど追いつけねぇ
I was able to graze it, but it got away from me!
What the hell is up with number nine and ten's fast attack?!
あの途中から来た９番１０番の速攻何なんだ
Don't act all cool, flunking tardy boys.
かこつけてんじゃねぇぞ赤点遅刻組
One lap of diving drills!
フライング一週
Yessir!
９セト目にしてやと初勝利か
We finally got our first win in our ninth set.
It's our first time not doing the penalty lap.
初のペナルティなしだな
I'm starving!
腹減た
Give us a good serve!
ナイサ
Looks like it's Ubugawa versus Nekoma over there.
駒か
Yaku, nice receive!
夜久さんナイスレシブ
That might be the last match for the night,
considering the time.
時間的にあれが今日のラストゲムかもな
Yeah.
In the second half, they were able to keep up with that fast attack.
後半もうあの速攻についてこられた
Date Tech,
伊達工
青城
Seijou,
and Inuoka from Nekoma.
駒の犬岡
I guess that fast attack won't work
forever against the better opponents.
やぱりあの速攻も強い相手にはいつまでも通用しない
Yaku! Nice receive!
夜久さんナイスレシブ
Huh?
あれ犬岡が控えにいる
Inuoka's on the sideline?
ブロク１枚
One blocker!
Go, Lev!
行けリエフ
All right!
よしゃあ
His arm is like a whip...
鞭みたいなスイング
すげぇ
Wow...
That number eleven...
あの１１番ぱと見猫背だから分かりにくいけど
At first glance, it's hard to tell because he's slouching, but he's pretty tall.
だいぶでかいよな１９０はあるか
He might be over 190 cm tall.
His arms and legs are so long.
手足長ぇ
何もんなんだあいつ
Who the heck is he?
Nekoma                           Ubugawa
よしゃあ
All right!
Seriously, what the hell is with that shrimpy
middle blocker and that setter from Karasuno?
またく何もんなんだ烏野のチビミドルブロカとセタ
翻弄されてたな
They were completely toying with you.
Shut up! Take a look at their fast attack up close!
うせぇ目の前であの速攻見てみろ
You wouldn't know what was going on!
何起こてか分かんねぇから
Man, this year looks like it's gonna be interesting.
いや今年は面白くなりそうだな
お疲れ様でした
Thank you for the matches!
Your fast attacks were amazing as always, Shouyou!
翔陽の速攻は相変わらずすごかたな
でもあれじゃ今までと変わらないんだ
But nothing's changed from before.
It's no different from back then.
あの時と変わらない
I came here to improve.
俺は強くなるためにここに来たんだ
Hey! Who the heck is that middle blocker of yours?
駒のミドルブロカて何者なんだ
Oh...
１年の灰リエフ
That's the first-year, Haiba Lev.
He's half Russian and half Japanese.
ロシア人と日本人のハフだよ
H-Half?! So cool!
ハフハフかけぇ
リエリ
L-Le...
Lev. What does it mean in Russian again? Tiger?
リエフ何だけロシア語で虎
It means lion!
獅子すねライオン
前の時はいなかたよな
He wasn't there last time, right?
Yeah. Lev started playing volleyball in high school.
リエフは高校からバレ始めたから
烏野に行たゴルデンウィクあたりはまだほぼ素人で
When we went to Karasuno around Golden Week, he still hadn't played very much, and only the regulars went.
あの時はベンチ入りメンバしかいてないからね
He's that good already?!
あれで高校から
Yeah.
Also, when we paired up in practice, we had a lot of trouble.
それなのに一緒に組まされたりして大変だた
No matter how hard I tried, our timing was always off.
合わせようとしてもタイミングいつもバラバラだたし
I'm used to it now, though.
もう慣れたけど
I see...
Kenma couldn't stop sighing.
研磨さん溜め息ばかついてましたもんね
研磨でも読めないことてあるんだな
I guess there are people even you can't read.
Lev is just too special.
リエフが特殊すぎるんだよ
今はほぼ元々の身体能力とセンスだけでやてるね
Right now, he's mostly working off his innate physical abilities and instincts.
後身長
And his height.
Yeah, his height totally isn't fair!
確かにあの身長はずるい分けて欲しい
I want some of that!
He's been blessed with too much!
いろいろ恵まれすぎすでも負けないす
But I'm not gonna lose!
まあ戦力になるし素直だし
Well, he's a powerful asset, honest, and not a bad guy.
嫌なやつじゃないよたまに素直すぎるけど
Though he's too honest at times.
Oh, he still sucks at passing the ball around, though.
あでもパスとかの基礎はまだ全然だめ
He's worse than you, Shouyou.
翔陽よりもだめ
His serves are worse than yours too.
サブも翔陽よりへたくそ
Am I your standard for crappy?!
研磨のへたくその基準は俺なのかよ
But you are bad.
Kenma's actually talking without being shy.
あの研磨が人見知りせずにしゃべてるよ
だて下手じゃん
Yeah.
Haiba... Haiba Lev, huh?
灰灰リエフか
Western names are so awesome...
横文字の名前かけぇな
There's... R-Russian! How do I greet in Russian?! Russian!
ロシア語ロシア語ロシア語の挨拶ロシア語
Karasuno's number ten.
烏野の１０番
日本語
Japanese?!
Oh, sorry. I can't speak Russian.
あごめんロシア語なら俺しゃべれない
I was born and raised in Japan.
日本生まれ日本育ち
I see!
そうなのか
Hey, how tall are you?
な身長何センチ
I'm Hinata Shouyou, a first-year.
俺日向翔陽１年
I was 194 cm tall the last time I checked.
この前１９４になてた
I'm Haiba Lev, a first-year.
俺灰リエフ１年
194 cm! Nice!
１９４いいな
You're even smaller up close, Hinata.
日向は近くで見ると余計に小さいな
What was that?! Eh?!
何だこら
ごごめん悪気はない
S-Sorry! I wasn't trying to insult you.
でも日向は余裕でここまで跳ぶだろさきの試合で見た
But you have no problem jumping this high, do you?
I saw that earlier today.
But I can jump even higher than that.
俺はそこから更に跳ぶけどな
Oww... Oww... Oww...
Then...
I'll jump even higher, to the very top!
俺は先に天辺まで跳ぶ
Your spikes were really cool, since you didn't
seem to care if there were blockers there or not.
お前のスパイクはブロクいてもお構いなして感じですごかた
Yeah, well...
うん俺は
音駒のエスだからな
I'm Nekoma's ace.
ていうと猛虎さんに怒られるけど
Though, when I say that, Taketora gets mad at me.
What? No one would call someone
who can barely play defense an ace!
守備もろくにできないやつはエスとは呼ばないです
でもリエフは俺と一緒でミドルブロカだろセンタだろ
But you're a middle blocker like me, right?
In the center, right?
駒のモヒカンの人とか
Aces are usually wing spikers like the mohawk guy on your team, right?
ウィングスパイカのことを言うだろ
ポジションの名前て関係ある
Do position names have anything to do with it?
The one who's able to score the most points is the ace, right?
一番たくさん点をもぎ取たやつがエスだろ
Simple as that.
単純
See you tomorrow.
じゃあまた明日な
日向のあの速攻明日一番に俺が止める
I'll be the first to stop that fast attack of yours tomorrow, Hinata.
"The one who's able to score the most points is the ace."
たくさんの点をもぎ取たやつがエス
With their own hands...
自分の手で
Ubugawa                  Karasuno
Bring it!
来いやあああ
All right!
おしゃ
Karasuno looks a lot calmer than they were during Golden Week.
烏野はゴルデンウィクの時より落ち着いて見えますね
Not to mention, they've got their number ten's fast attack.
それに相変わらずのあの１０番の速攻
Yeah. They seem much more consistent now.
ああそうね全体的に安定感が出てきたね
But are you content with that, Karasuno?
だがそれでいいのか烏野
You lost with your current strength, didn't you?
今あるその力で負けてきたのだろ
Isn't that why you came here to improve?
だから強くなるためにここへ来たのだろ
All right! Our opponents still aren't able to counter your deviant fast attack, so keep on using it!
おし相手はまだ変人速攻に全然対応できてねぇ
ガンガン使ていけ
Yes, sir!
Yes, sir.
Need a towel?
タオルいる
Oh, sure.
ああはい
Number four!
４番
It's in the air! Kenma, cover it!
上がた研磨カバ
Left! Left!
レフトレフト
Give it to me!
俺に寄越せ
しゃあ
All right!
ナイスキリエフ
Nice spike, Lev!
Sorry for being rude.
溜め口すんません調子こきました
I overstepped my bounds.
Don't I keep telling you not to worry about it?
そういうのいいていつも言てんじゃん
The bigger problem is how you suddenly wanted to do a broad jump.
それよりブロドなんて突然言われても困る
So that thing just now is called a broad jump?
今のブロドて言うんすかかけぇ
That's so awesome!
That broad jump was spur-of-the-moment?
ぶつけのブロドだたのかよ
But we were able to do it.
でもできたじゃないすか
駒のエスだからな
I'm Nekoma's ace.
センタエス
A center ace...
ほら研磨次サブ
Kenma! It's your turn to serve!
We lost in the interhigh preliminaries.
俺達はインハイ予選で負けた
What choices do we need to make to progress?
先に進むために選ぶべきは何か
I'm not sure if it's the correct path,
Kenma! Give us another good serve!
正しいかどうかは分からないが
研磨さん一本ナイサ
but we've got new blood flowing through our veins.
俺達は新しい血液が回り始めた
Does Karasuno want to improve by becoming more consistent?
烏野が強さを手に入れるために求めるのは
安定か
Or do they...
それとも
進化か
want to evolve?
Lev's finally blending in with the team.
リエフもだいぶチムに馴染んできたよな
Yeah, even though it's little by little.
うんちょとずつだけどね
That's not true!
そんなことないです
Oh? Do you feel like you're not quite there yet?
自分じゃまだまだて感じか
I'm already an indispensable part of the team! The ace.
既にチムに不可欠な存在エスなんで
You're an ace at not understanding the position you play, maybe.
確かに自己認識の甘さはエス級だわ
Episode Five:
"Greed"
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
次回ハイキュ『欲』
"'Greed.'"